An honest man caught in a world of intrigue, power and passion.
The Dancer Upstairs is a crime, drama, romance film directed by John Malkovich.
A police detective in a South American country is dedicated to
hunting down a revolutionary guerilla leader.
Agustín Rejas, played by Javier Bardem.
Sucre, played by Juan Diego Botto.
Yolanda, played by Laura Morante.
Llosa, played by Elvira Mínguez.
Sylvina Rejas, played by Alexandra Lencastre.
Merino, played by Oliver Cotton.
The Dancer Upstairs is a 2002 Spanish-American crime thriller film produced and directed by John Malkovich
(in his directorial debut), and starring Javier Bardem, Juan Diego Botto and Laura Morante.
The film is an adaptation of the 1995 novel The Dancer Upstairs by
Nicholas Shakespeare, who also wrote the screenplay.
The tone is emotional and intense.